Weird sex · Obsession · Comic books
Crumb is a documentary film directed by Terry Zwigoff.
This movie chronicles the life and times of R.
Robert Crumb is the cartoonist/artist who drew Keep On Truckin', Fritz the Cat, and
played a major pioneering role in the genesis of underground comix.
Through interviews with his mother, two brothers, wife, ex-wife and ex-girlfriends, as well as selections from his
vast quantity of graphic art, we are treated to a darkly comic ride through one man's subconscious mind.
Self, played by Robert Crumb.
Self, played by Aline Kominsky.
Self, played by Charles Crumb.
Self, played by Maxon Crumb.
Self, played by Robert Hughes.
Self, played by Martin Müller.
Crumb is a 1994 American documentary film about
the noted underground cartoonist R.
Crumb and his family (including his two brothers) and his outlook on life.
Directed by Terry Zwigoff and produced by Lynn
O'Donnell, it won widespread acclaim.
It was released on the film festival circuit in September 1994 before being released theatrically in the United States on
April 28, 1995, having been screened at film festivals (and winning the Documentary Prize at Sundance) that year.
Anderson (later critic for the San Francisco Examiner) placed the film on his list of the ten greatest films of all time, labeling it
"the greatest documentary ever made." The Criterion Collection released the film on DVD and Blu-ray on August 10, 2010.
The film explores themes of underground, san
francisco, california, fetish, artist, nerd.
The tone is dark.